Guide to the Campus Ministry Advancement Records
Yale University Divinity School Library
Campus Ministry Advancement Records
1967-2009
RG 259
Yale University Divinity School Library
1.5
(3 boxes)
This collection documents the history and operations of Campus Ministry Advancement, an organization incorporated in Ohio in 1967 to support Christian ministries in higher education. Legal documents, minutes, correspondence, financial records, and tax records are included.
Campus Ministry Advancement
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Campus Ministry Advancement, Inc. 2014.
Biographical / Historical
Campus Ministry Advancement (CMA) was founded by Reverend John W. Miller in 1954 as a non-profit organization. Based in Columbus, Ohio, it became incorporated in 1967. The organization was established to support Christian ministries in higher education. CMA provided grants related to support for persons engaged in Christian ministry in post secondary education and organized training events for skills in development and fundraising for staff and boards of such ministries. CMA was organized to "teach, promote, and advance the Christian religion among residents and citizens of the U.S.A. and especially among the youth."
Scope and Contents
The collection includes documents related to the establishment of the organization, minutes, correspondence about the program, and financial and tax records. Series I contains organizational records dating from 1967 to 2007. Documents in this series include legal and historical documents including Articles of Incorporation and Code of Regulations and minutes from Board of Trustees and Membership meetings. Series II contains correspondence dating from 1967 to 2007. Documents included are letters to and from Director John Miller, letters to and from Director Carolyn Miller, and letters to and from President Robert Epps. The correspondence deals with administrative matters, grant requests, fundraising seminars, and conferences. Series III contains contains financial records dating from 1967 to 2009. Documents include bank and investment records, financial reports, budgets, treasurer's reports, and records of disbursed grants. Series IV contains tax records dating from 1969 to 2009. Included within this series are correspondence with the Internal Revenue Service, 990 forms, and correspondence with attorneys.
Arrangement
I. Organizational Records
II. Correspondence
III. Financial Records
IV. Tax Records
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Church work with students -- United States; Campus Ministry Advancement
- Organizational Records, Series I
  - Legal and historical documents
    - Articles of Incorporation; Amendments to Articles of Incorporation; Registration as Charitable Trust, 1967-1982 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Code of Regulations, no date (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - "Background Information Concerning Campus Ministry Advancement, Inc." by Jon and Carolyn Miller; Will of and information about benefactor Margaret J. Davis; historical statement by Carolyn Miller, 1969-1994 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Statements regarding purpose and program of organization; lists of members of Board of Trustees, 1984-1998, no date (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Minutes and Reports
    - Minutes of organizational meeting, 1967 Dec 14 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Minutes of Board of Trustees meetings and records of "Action without Meeting", 1967, 1969, 1970, 1975, 1980-1989 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Minutes of Board of Trustees meetings and records of "Action without Meeting"; agenda for conference call, 1990-1995, 1997, 2006, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Minutes of Annual Meeting of Members, 1969, 1970, 1975, 1981, 1984, 1985, 1987-1995 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Programs and fundraising
    - Fund-raising training events; article by Robert Epps, 1987, no date (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Grant criteria, papers from "Conversation on Ministry in Higher Education" convened by Ohio Synod of Presbyterian Church, collected material re. ministry in higher education, 1985, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Correspondence, Series II
  - Letters to/from Director John Miller, regarding establishing Articles of Incorporation, staffing information, 1967-1984 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Letters to/from Director Carolyn Miller, regarding grant requests, reporting to Trust Officer, adminstrative matters, 1985-1989 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Letters to/from Director Carolyn Miller, regarding grant requests, fund-raising seminars, administrative matters, 1990 Jan-Jun (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Letters to/from Director Carolyn Miller, regarding grant requests, fund-raising seminars, administrative matters, 1990 Jun-Oct (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Letters to/from Director Carolyn Miller, regarding grant requests, fund-raising seminars, administrative matters, 1990 Nov-Dec (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Letters to/from Carolyn Miller and President Robert Epps, regarding administrative matters, scholarship and grant requests, programs, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Letters to/from President Robert Epps, regarding administrative matters, scholarship and grant requests, programs, 1992-1993 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Letters to/from President Robert Epps, regarding donations and grant requests, adminstrative matters, 1994-1996 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Letters to/from President Robert Epps, regarding donations and grant requests, adminstrative matters, 1997-1999 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Letters to/from President Robert Epps, regarding donations and grant requests, adminstrative matters, participation in Global Multifaith Conference, Vancouver, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Letters to/from President Robert Epps, regarding donations to Carolyn Miller Memorial, grant requests, adminstrative matters, programs, 2001-2002 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Letters to/from President Robert Epps grant requests, reimbursements, adminstrative matters, report to Board, 2004-2007, no date (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Financial Records, Series III
  - Financial ledger sheets, 1967-1984, 1990-1991 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Treasurer's reports, records of grants disbursed, 1967-1984 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Treasurer's reports, records of grants disbursed, 1985-1991 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Financial reports, budgets, 1992-1999 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Financial reports, budgets, 2000-2009 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Bank and investment records, 1987-1994 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Bank and investment records, 1995-2002 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Bank and investment records, 2003-2006 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Bank and investment records, 2007-2009 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Tax Records, Series IV
  - 990 forms, correspondence with Internal Revenue Service, 1969-1973 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 990 forms, correspondence with Internal Revenue Service, 1976-1979 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - 990 forms, correspondence with Internal Revenue Service, attorneys, 1980-1981 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - 990 forms, correspondence with Internal Revenue Service, attorneys, 1982-1984 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - 990 forms, correspondence with Internal Revenue Service, attorneys, bank regarding charitable status, 1985-1989 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - 990 forms, correspondence, 1990-1992 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - 990 forms, correspondence, 1993-1996 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - 990 forms, correspondence, 1997-1999 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - 990 forms, correspondence, 2000-2009 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Addendum - 2018, Series V
  - Legal documents, 1967-1970 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Legal documents and correspondence, 1995-2005 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Minutes and documents from meetings of Board and Members, 1995-2005 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Regarding dissolution of Campus Ministry Advancement organization and dispersal of remaining funds, 2112-2117 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Program documentation, 1990-2007 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Financial records, 1967-2017 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Tax records, 1997-2016 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous documents and correspondence (on USB drive), 2005-2017 (Box 4, Folder 8)